

Summary

7 years of experience in backend, DevOps, and data engineering technologies.

Eager to continuously learn while working on meaningful projects within a team.

Highly values a culture built on empathy, feedback and knowledge sharing.

Contact



🗍 +41-78-226-9371

Zürich, Switzerland

zoltan.umlauf@gmail.com

in /in/zoltan-umlauf

Languages

English: full professional proficiency

German: elementary proficiency Hungarian: native proficiency

Interests

- Table tennis
- Reading
- · Board games
- Hiking
- Logic puzzles
- · Software craftsmanship

Zoltán Umlauf

Senior Software Engineer

Work Experience



Senior Software Engineer

@ UBS (employed by EPAM)

Zürich, 02/2023 - Present C

- Contributed to a suite of services responsible for sourcing Swiss client data for a complex Anti-Money Laundering (AML) model.
- Built GitLab CI/CD pipelines from scratch, enhancing deployment efficiency and establishing a robust workflow for our team.
- Advocated for the importance of fast feedback loops and engineers owning their code in production, even in a regulated industry.
- Fostered good relationships with developers from the upstream team, ensuring satisfactory coordination between our teams.

📚 Java 17, Spring Boot, Maven, Python, Azure Cloud, Databricks, Gitlab CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Linux, Elasticsearch, **PostgreSQL**

Senior Software Engineer

@ Turbine Al

Budapest, 09/2021 - 01/2023 0

- Designed and developed new features in Turbine's human cell simulation platform, making the jobs of biologists more efficient.
- · Constructed machine learning problems to train deep learning models. Evaluated these models on various success criteria.
- Explored various technologies, such as version-controlled databases, while gaining insights into human cell modeling and the drug discovery process.
- Significantly improved the quality of existing production code.
- Performed a wide range of data engineering tasks.

Python, Poetry, Pandas, Azure Cloud, AzureML, Databricks, Airflow, GitHub Actions, Terraform, Linux, Dolt, MongoDB

Senior Software Developer

@ Grape Solutions

Budapest, 03/2019 - 08/2021 0

- Developed Mobiliti, the largest provider of electric vehicle charging and other e-mobility services in Hungary.
- Discussed software architecture decisions with the team.
- Improved the development workflow, which reduced the complexity of our releases and increased productivity.
- · Documented important domain knowledge, promoted knowledge sharing and gathering practices.
- Planned and executed the integration with 4 Charge Point Operators.
- · Learned the basics of DevOps with Docker and Kubernetes.

Java 11, Kotlin, Spring Boot 2, OAuth 2.0, Liquibase, JUnit5, Mockito, Wiremock, Gradle, Docker, Ansible, Google Cloud Platform (PubSub, Firestore), MySQL, MongoDB, Python

Software Developer

@ AITIA International

Budapest, 06/2017 - 02/2019 Q

- Participated in a European research and innovation project with 108 partners from over 19 countries. Contributed to the design and development of a framework for the project over the span of 3 years. Familiarized new partners with the framework and reviewed code written by them.
- Analysed large amounts of CAN bus data from a German forklift manufacturing company. Communicated with the company representatives to gain domain knowledge. Created classical machine learning models to help reduce forklift maintenance costs.
- 🥏 Java 8, JAX-RS, Spring Boot 2, Hibernate, Maven, RabbitMQ, R

Education

MSc in Electrical Engineering

@ Budapest University of Technology and Economics 02/2016 - 01/2018

• Thesis: Data processing methods and solutions in IoT based Cyber-Physical Systems

BSc in Electrical Engineering

@ Budapest University of Technology and Economics

09/2012 - 01/2016 ¢

• Thesis: Messaging system aided by speech recognition on Android

